<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Console Quest</title>
    <link href="https://consolequest.net/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://consolequest.net" />
    <updated>2025-05-25T16:41:59+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Juri Steiner</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://consolequest.net</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Console Quest #1: First Post Ever (No, Really)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Juri Steiner</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://consolequest.net/console-quest-1-first-post-ever-no-really.html"/>
        <id>https://consolequest.net/console-quest-1-first-post-ever-no-really.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://consolequest.net/media/posts/2/matthieu-beaumont-iYnpYeyu57k-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="truenas"/>
            <category term="selfhosting"/>
            <category term="introduction"/>
            <category term="homelab"/>
            <category term="docker"/>

        <updated>2025-05-24T23:43:13+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://consolequest.net/media/posts/2/matthieu-beaumont-iYnpYeyu57k-unsplash.jpg" alt="Dark datacenter with glowing green and red server LEDs, cables and hardware creating a cyberpunk atmosphere" />
                    Hello World This is awkward. I’m starting a tech blog, but I’ve&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://consolequest.net/media/posts/2/matthieu-beaumont-iYnpYeyu57k-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Dark datacenter with glowing green and red server LEDs, cables and hardware creating a cyberpunk atmosphere" /></p>
                <h1 id="hello-world">Hello World</h1>
<p>This is awkward. I’m starting a tech blog, but I’ve never actually written a blog post before. Unless you count that LinkedIn rant about Burger King’s Pfand system where none of the staff knew they were supposed to take back reusable cups because apparently everyone just uses paper cups - which, let’s be honest, was peak content and deserved more engagement.</p><p>So here we are. My first real post. Ever.</p><h2 id="why-am-i-doing-this">Why Am I Doing This?</h2>
<p>Good question. I spend way too much time tinkering with selfhosted services, Docker containers, and automation setups. Currently running dozens of containers across various services, and honestly, most of this happens in isolation - me, a Dockge interface, and an increasingly complex TrueNAS setup that probably uses more electricity than it should.</p><p>I figured: why not document this chaos? Maybe someone else is on the same journey. Maybe not. Either way, at least I’ll have a record of all the times I broke my setup and somehow fixed it at 2 AM.</p><h2 id="the-console-quest-name">The “Console Quest” Name</h2>
<p>Yeah, it’s a bit dramatic. But if you’ve ever spent three hours debugging why your Docker container won’t start, only to realize you had a typo in your compose file, you’ll understand. It really is a quest. An endless, sometimes maddening quest for the perfect setup.</p><p>Plus, “My Dozens of Containers Homelab Adventures” was too long for a domain name.</p><h2 id="what-im-actually-working-with">What I’m Actually Working With</h2>
<p>Since this is supposedly a tech blog, here’s my current setup:</p><p><strong>Core Infrastructure:</strong></p><blockquote>
<p><strong>Main server:</strong> TrueNAS Scale → Intel i5-7400T, 32GB RAM, ~50TB raw storage across multiple pools<br><strong>Onsite backup:</strong> TrueNAS Scale → Celeron N5100, 4GB RAM<br><strong>Offsite backup:</strong> Old QNAP running TrueNAS Scale → located in neighbor’s house with underground LAN cable (yes, really)<br><strong>Home Assistant:</strong> Dedicated Raspberry Pi 4 → separation of concerns and all that<br><strong>Zigbee coordinator:</strong> CC2652P2-TCP from cod.m → proper network-based coordinator<br><strong>Workstation:</strong> AMD Ryzen 5 7500F, 32GB RAM, RX 6750 XT → gaming rig that occasionally does work<br><strong>Internet:</strong> 500+ Mbps fiber connection → because waiting for downloads is for peasants<br><strong>Network:</strong> UniFi infrastructure → gateway, managed switches, multiple access points
<strong>Backup strategy:</strong> Proper 3-2-1 across multiple buildings</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Container Management:</strong></p><blockquote>
<p><strong>Platform:</strong> Dockge → because TrueNAS’s Docker UI… isn’t great<br><strong>Scale:</strong> Dozens of containers → and counting<br><strong>Architecture:</strong> Separate prod and dev environments → finally learning proper practices</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Services Running:</strong></p><blockquote>
<p><strong>Media:</strong> Jellyfin, Immich<br><strong>Home Automation:</strong> Full-house Home Assistant setup → solar/battery management, heat pump integration, comprehensive Zigbee network, and way too many entities that need proper labeling (ongoing project…)<br><strong>Energy Management:</strong> Solar production, battery storage, heat pump monitoring<br><strong>Productivity:</strong> Paperless, WikiJS<br><strong>Monitoring:</strong> Uptime Kuma, Scrutiny<br><strong>Development:</strong> Code Server, various test containers<br><strong>Networking:</strong> Tailscale router<br><strong>And way too many others…</strong></p></blockquote>
<h2 id="what-this-blog-will-be">What This Blog Will Be</h2>
<p>Honestly? Documentation of my ongoing homelab journey. Probably:</p><ul>
<li>Docker Compose files that actually work</li>
<li>TrueNAS + Dockge tutorials</li>
<li>Home automation experiments</li>
<li>“Here’s how I broke everything this week” posts</li>
<li>Reviews of selfhosted alternatives to popular services</li>
</ul>
<p>No promises on posting schedule. No promises I won’t accidentally delete everything while “improving” the setup.</p><h2 id="why-publii-and-not-ghost">Why Publii (And Not Ghost)?</h2>
<p>Speaking of services - this blog is powered by Publii, which is ironic since I literally have Ghost running in my homelab. But after spending my days managing containers and configs, sometimes you just want a desktop app that generates static files and doesn’t require a database.</p><p>Don’t judge me. Even Docker enthusiasts need GUIs sometimes.</p><h2 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h2>
<p>I’m planning to document my current stack, share some working Docker Compose setups, and maybe explain why I chose Dockge over Portainer (spoiler: easier backups and cleaner compose file management).</p><p>We’ll see how long this lasts. My track record with “I’ll definitely document this properly” projects isn’t great.</p><p>But hey, at least I finally started.</p><hr>
<p><em>Since I have literally zero readers right now, I’ll just say: if you somehow found this, hello! What’s running in your homelab? I’d love to hear about your own console quest adventures.</em></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
