<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Console Quest</title>
    <link href="https://consolequest.net/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://consolequest.net" />
    <updated>2025-05-29T13:30:01+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Juri Steiner</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://consolequest.net</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Console Quest #1: First Post Ever</title>
        <author>
            <name>Juri Steiner</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://consolequest.net/console-quest-1-first-post-ever-no-really.html"/>
        <id>https://consolequest.net/console-quest-1-first-post-ever-no-really.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://consolequest.net/media/posts/2/matthieu-beaumont-iYnpYeyu57k-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="truenas"/>
            <category term="selfhosting"/>
            <category term="introduction"/>
            <category term="homelab"/>
            <category term="docker"/>

        <updated>2025-05-24T23:43:13+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://consolequest.net/media/posts/2/matthieu-beaumont-iYnpYeyu57k-unsplash.jpg" alt="Dark datacenter with glowing green and red server LEDs, cables and hardware creating a cyberpunk atmosphere" />
                    Hello World This is awkward. I’m starting a tech blog, but I’ve&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://consolequest.net/media/posts/2/matthieu-beaumont-iYnpYeyu57k-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Dark datacenter with glowing green and red server LEDs, cables and hardware creating a cyberpunk atmosphere" /></p>
                <h1 id="hello-world">Hello World</h1>
<p>This is awkward. I’m starting a tech blog, but I’ve never actually written a blog post before. Unless you count that LinkedIn rant about Burger King’s Pfand system where none of the staff knew they were supposed to take back reusable cups because apparently everyone just uses paper cups - which, let’s be honest, was peak content and deserved more engagement.</p><p>So here we are. My first real post. Ever.</p><h2 id="why-am-i-doing-this">Why Am I Doing This?</h2>
<p>Good question. I spend way too much time tinkering with selfhosted services, Docker containers, and automation setups. Currently running way too many containers across various services - I stopped counting after #47, but my electricity bill hasn’t. Honestly, most of this happens in isolation - me, a Dockge interface, and an increasingly complex TrueNAS setup that probably uses more electricity than it should.</p><p>I figured: why not document this chaos? Maybe someone else is on the same journey. Maybe not. Either way, at least I’ll have a record of all the times I broke my setup and somehow fixed it at 2 AM.</p><h2 id="the-console-quest-name">The “Console Quest” Name</h2>
<p>Yeah, it’s a bit dramatic. But if you’ve ever spent three hours debugging why your Docker container won’t start, only to realize you had a typo in your compose file, you’ll understand. It really is a quest. An endless, sometimes maddening quest for the perfect setup.</p><p>Plus, “My Dozens of Containers Homelab Adventures” was too long for a domain name.</p><h2 id="why-english">Why English?</h2>
<p>But Juri you ask, you are german, why do you write in English, did you feel fancy today?
Actually, there is more than one reason for this.
First and foremost, my brain thinks in english at the moment it comes to tech. 90% of what I read, watch or hear regarding tech is in english. Be it official documentation, Hardware Heaven or Two and a Half Admins.
Second, I want to hone my english skills. Reading is good, but actually putting out something will hopefully do me some good in that regard.
Last but not least, if I actually want to have a glimpse of hope at least someone is reading this, I better write it in some kind of “universal language”. And like it or not, that has to be english.</p><h2 id="but-youre-using-ai-right">But you’re using AI, right?</h2>
<p>Yeah, of course I am. I also use autocorrect. And a computer. I’m not gonna write my posts by hand, like a caveman. But while you’re asking: I write my posts myself, but heavily use AI to correct, structure and overall iterate over the posts. I also use it for research and for analysis.</p><h2 id="what-this-blog-will-be">What This Blog Will Be</h2>
<p>Honestly? Documentation of my ongoing homelab journey. Probably:</p><blockquote>
<p><strong>Docker Configs:</strong> Compose files that actually work → Copy-paste ready setups</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>TrueNAS Guides:</strong> TrueNAS + Dockge tutorials → Real world configurations  </p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Home Automation:</strong> Automation experiments → Home Assistant deep dives</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Learning Logs:</strong> “Here’s how I broke everything this week” posts → Honest troubleshooting</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Random Projects:</strong> Various shenanigans → Whatever catches my attention</p></blockquote>
<p>No promises on posting schedule. No promises I won’t accidentally delete everything while “improving” the setup.</p><h2 id="why-publii-and-not-ghost">Why Publii (And Not Ghost)?</h2>
<p>Speaking of services - this blog is powered by Publii, which is ironic since I literally have Ghost running in my homelab. But after spending my nights managing containers and configs, sometimes you just want a desktop app that generates static files and doesn’t require a database.</p><p>Don’t judge me! Doing it this way dramatically increases the likelihood of this staying up.</p><h2 id="current-setup">Current Setup</h2>
<p>Since we’re talking infrastructure, here’s what’s currently running this whole operation:</p><blockquote>
<p><strong>Blog Platform:</strong> Publii static generator → Desktop app, no database drama</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Hosting:</strong> GitHub Pages → Free, reliable, plays nice with custom domains  </p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Domain:</strong> consolequest.net → Because “MyContainersAreMultiplying.com” was taken</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Theme:</strong> Mono → Clean, fast, doesn’t get in the way of the content</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Homelab:</strong> TrueNAS Scale + Dockge → Where the real magic (and chaos) happens</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h2>
<p>I’m planning to document my current stack, share some working Docker Compose setups, and maybe explain why I chose Dockge over Portainer (spoiler: easier backups and cleaner compose file management).</p><p>We’ll see how long this lasts. My track record with “I’ll definitely document this properly” projects is a mixed bag.</p><p>But hey, at least I finally started.</p><hr>
<p><em>Since I have literally zero readers right now, I’ll just say: if you somehow found this, hello! What’s running in your homelab? I’d love to hear about your own console quest adventures.</em></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
